#### SENIOR DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER · PYTHON

4/3/h/46, Bhukailash Road, Kolkata-700023, West Bengal, INDIA

🛮 (+92) 7799126262 | 🗷 abhishekjaiswal.kol@gmail.com | 🌴 jkabhishek.github.io/ | 🖸 jkabhishek | 🛅 abhishek-jaiswal

### Summary\_

7+ years experience specializing in backend/infrastructure, web development and computer security. Super nerd who loves Sublime, Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

### Ski**lls**

**Thorough knowledge of** Python, Ansible, Javascript, PHP

adept at frameworks like django, webpy, flask, Symfony2, Codeigniter, CakePhp

**Technically sound with** Linux, Networking, Kubernetes, Docker **Adept with tools and utilities like** Pycharm, Sublime, Vim, Eclipse, Iterm,

Adroit with source code management using GIT, SVN High potential to utilize scripting languages HTML, XML

**Proficient in Operating Sytem like** Windows xp/7/8, Ubuntu, OSX

## Work Experience\_

#### **Pramati Technologies**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER [PYTHON]

Hyderabad, Telangana, INDIA

Apr., 2015 - PRESENT

- Implemented djangorestframework RESTful API server for internal projects.
- Implemented Data driven Framework in python/djangorestframework frontend/backend.
- Worked on Automation Framework in Ansible to deploy Openstack for one of the largest Telecom Provider.
- · Worked on several POC projects in Docker, Kubernetes, ansible, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Developed an easy-to-use Payment module which connects to major PG(Payment Gateway).

MindFire Solutions

Bhubaneswar, Orrisa, INDIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER [PYTHON]

Nov. 2012 - Apr. 2015

Jun, 2010 - Nov. 2012

- Worked on several Odoo (formerly openerp) projects.
- · Worked on Customized ERP Application for Custom Brokerage and warehousing using odoo framework in python.
- Worked on Web based ERP Solutions for Importers and Exporters using PHP, EXTjs, Mysql.

### **Acumen Consultancy PvtLtd**

Kolkata, WestBengal, INDIA

WEB ENGINEER [PHP]

- Worked on IMS-Pharmastat, web based CMS using PHP (Codeigniter), Javascript, Mysql. (http://imspharmastat.fr/)
- Worked on UBI-France, Web Based Doctor Directory Listing using PHP (Codeigniter), Javascript, Mysql.
- Worked on Open2leads, Question and Answer Forum for B2B with social-networking features, Using PHP (symfony), JavaScript, MySQL.

## **Education**

### **Institute Of Engineering & management**

Kolkata, WestBengal, INDIA

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (MCA)

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (BCA)

2009 - 2011

• Major in Computer Applications

Acharya Institute of Management & Sciences, Bangalore University,

Bangalore, Karnatka, INDIA

2006 - 2009

• Major in Computer Applications

WBCHSE, (West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education)

Kolkata, WestBengal, INDIA

HIGHER SECONDARY, PUC

· Accounts Major

2004 - 2006

# Achievements

2016	RED HAT CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR IN RED HAT OPENSTACK,
	https://www.redhat.com/rhtapps/certification/verify/?certId=160-236-972
2017	<b>Learn DevOps: The Complete Kubernetes</b> , https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-L2FLIMPW/
2012	Zend Certified Php5 Developer, ClientCandidateID=ZEND023657
2012	Microsoft Certified Developer, Microsoft Certification ID: 9784595
2012	certified in ERP-Essential (Microsoft Dynamics),
2010	${\bf Runner\ up\ Embedding\ System\ Programming\ inter-college\ held\ in\ IEM\ post-graduate\ level},$
2007	College Festival Organizer,
2007	Undergraduate level College Festival organizer,